Ilya Dyakov

dyak.ilya@gmail.com | 619-592-3509 | San Diego, CA

Objective

IT Engineer with over 13 years of experience in installing and maintaining hardware, software, peripherals, and networks.

Advanced troubleshooting and learning abilities, punctual and responsible. Fluent in English, native speaker of Russian. Ability to learn quickly and work independently.

Summary of Qualifications

Expertise in building and managing corporate networks, installing and maintaining Windows/Linux servers, and VMWare virtualization.

In-depth knowledge of 2G – 5G base structure and development.

Customer support.

Servers maintenance in the DATA center

Experience working with a big amount of data, building automation data validation and comparison tools and performing statistical data analysis

Experience with low-power circuit design, DC/DC converters, power management methods. Experience in designing products for wireless networks (GSM, LTE), GPS, WiFi, and Bluetooth wireless systems.

Technical Skills

Programming Languages: Python, Bash, Perl, SQL

Operating Systems Linux CentOS 5-7, Red Hat, Ubuntu, Debian, Windows Server 2000-2012

Developer Tools: Visual Studio, PyCharm, Kubernetes

Test automation tools: Visual Studio Unit Testing Framework (MSTest)

Defect tracking tools: Visual Studio Team Services (VSTS), Jira

Databases: PostgreSQL, MySQL

Cloud: AWS

Other VMWare vSphere 4-6, LAN/WAN (switching and routing), TCPIP (DNS/DHCP/NAT/Firewall), Wireshark, 2-5G Technology, REST, SOAP, HTML, CSS, XML, JIRA, Ansible.

Professional Experience:

Site reliability engineer | InfoMarket web studio | Jan 2018 - PRESENT

- Monitored network infrastructure of the enterprise, to ensure optimal performance of network equipment and server Docker services.
- Installation, configuration and maintenance of Windows servers (application servers, remote desktop servers, database servers (MSSQL), web servers (Apache)).
- Installation, configuration and maintenance of Linux web servers (CentOS, Red Hat, Debian, Ubuntu).
- Configuration active components of the corporate network (VLAN).

DevOps | CJSC MegaLabs, Moscow | December 2014 - December 2017

- Linux SW Development and Linux Network Administration (DNS, DHCP, File Server, Print Server, Bash and Python scripts)
- Knowledge of IP, UDP, TCP, HTTP protocols and analysis tools such as Wireshark
- Installation, configuration, diagnostics Windows systems
- Network error solution (tcpdump, traceroute, telnet, ping, mtr, wireshark, iptables)
- Development and support of MS Hyper-V, ProxMox, VMware WS, VirtualBox, Selenium
- Logs troubleshooting
- Maintenance and repair IT hardware

- Support customers
- SAymon, Nagios system monitoring, Development
- Environment: C#, Python, Visual Studio, Pycharm, MySQL, Docker, Windows, Kubernetes

Technical Support Engineer | Devino Telecom, Moscow | June 2014 - December 2014

- Processing of customer requests through the HP-CRM system, by e-mail, live chat and phone calls with customer
- Tracking changes in the status of requests, monitoring the timing of request processing
- Tracking and providing operation information on accidents and failure
- Setup and support different Linux-based services as Apache, PostgeSQL
- Troubleshooting via Wireshark app
- Customer support

Senior engineer of the Testing Laboratory | Science and Technology Centers (Electronics test lab) | September 2009 - April 2014

- Repair and calibrate Measurement equipment Hewlett Packard (Agilent), Rohde and Schwarz, troubleshooting techniques and testing methods to component level.
- Successfully installation system main telecom operators Nokia Siemens Networks, Nokia FlexiHopper equipment and mobile terminals in Berlin (Germany)
- Maintenance of Measurement equipment (frequency counters, spectrum analyzers, HF and LF generators)
- Installation, configuration, maintenance of Windows, Linux

Senior QA Engineer | Otan-Security (Electronics test center) | June 2006 - September 2009

- Repair and calibrate RBS of 2G 3G base station.
- Soldering SMD components on PCBs
- Assemble hardware/equipment which is needed for test operations
- Performing a variety of related duties in support of stage testing, as well as testing site wide, as needed
- Collaborating with engineers to develop and document activities
- Using power tools, hand tools, and calibrated tooling (Oscilloscope)

Education

Bachelor in Electronics, Telecommunications and Information Technology | 2010 | Kazakhstan-American University, B.A.

Associate degree – technician/radio mechanic, specialization in Technical Servicing and Maintenance of Radio and Electronic Equipment | 2007 | Almaty State College of Energy and Electronic Technologies

Certification/Courses

2014 Interconnecting Cisco Networking Devices (ICND1, ICND2) v2.0

2015 Enterprise Linux System Administration (GL250)

2015 HP Accelerated SAN Essentials

2015 HP-UX System and Network Administration for Experienced UNIX System

Administrators

2016 Linux Troubleshooting (GL314)

2017 VMware Vsphere: Fast Track V6.0

2017 Introduction to PostgreSQL Administration

2018 Linux System Administration

2018 Mobile application Developer